

MD NURUL HASAN

I want to engage myself in the field of Mechanical engineering where I explore my talent and my knowledge. I want to enhance my knowledge to develop my career. So, I would like to join a field where I can use my skills and experiences and render my services to humankind most efficiently as a potential and an innovative engineer.



Uttar Bishil, Road No-1, Sornali Tower, Mirpur-1, Dhaka-1216.



July 22, 1993



01552320550 hasan.iiumg1739013@gmail.com

SOCIAL MEDIA



linkedin.com/in/md-nurulhasan



live: hasan.iiumg1739013

EDUCATION

07.2009 - 07.2011

Dhaka Residential Model College

HSC (Science)

05.2012 - 02.2017

Chittagong University of Engineering & Technology

Mechanical Engineering

2018 - present

International Islamic University Malaysia

Automotive Engineering (Research Mode)

Already submitted the thesis, waiting for viva.

EXPERIENCE

BIT AC-Bangladesh Industrial and Training Assistance Center Dhaka

Student-Industrial attachment

• Industrial training for 3 weeks

03.2017 - 02.2018

PRAN-RFL GROUP (Saudi Lubricant Section)

Operation assistant manager

- I look after all the industries Gas and Diesel generator engine oil and all industries compressor's oil and collect data from in-charge staff.
- Developing the new design of Mobil oil product and customize with newly developed can and also working with the marketing department to create new advertising for the product and quality.

2018 - present

International Islamic University of Malaysia

Research Assistant

Working with an electric vehicle team to developing gearbox and transmission systems.

10.2019 - present

Universal Cellular Engineering Services Sdn Bhd

Part-time Subcon

BACHELORS PROJECT

 Fabrication of a UAV with locating its position 'Supervised by TILOK KUMAR DAS, Assistant professor Department of Mechanical Engineering Chittagong University of Engineering & Technology (CUET).



POST-GRADUATE PROJECT

Development of Autonomous Electromagnetic 2 speed Gearbox for EV 'supervised by Prof. Dr. MD Ataur Rahman, Department of Mechanical Engineering, IIUM.

PUBLICATION

- Rahman A., Hassan N., Jaafar AH, Mohiuddin AKM, & Izan SI Study on the development of electromagnetic two speed gearbox for EV. ISSN: 2277-3878, Volume-7, Issue-6S, March 2019.
- Ataur Rahman *, MD Nurul Hasan , Mohd Zaki (2020). Modeling and validation of electric vehicle driveline architecture using bond graph. ISSN: 0193 - 4120 Page No. 15154 - 15167.
- ME-3913 entitled "Artificial Intelligent Embedded Iot Based Two Speed Electromagnetic Gearbox" IJTECH under review
- Ataur Rahman *, Nurul Hassan , Abdul Hassan Jaafar, AKM Mohiuddin, Sany Ihsan Izan "Study on the development of electromagnetic two-speed gearbox for EV". Manuscript (Ref. No. 2020 / BP / 5116D) is provisionally ACCEPTED for publication as a book chapter in the following book: Recent Developments in Engineering Research.

LANGUAGES

English



Bengali



SKILLS

- ✓ Good communication skills.
- ✓ Leadership and teamwork mentality.
- ✓ Interested in new research and take challenges.
- ✓ Interested to improve problem-solving skills.
- ✓ Effective interpersonal skills and flexibility.
- ✓ Solid Works, Ms-Excel, Ms-word

HOBBY











Technology

Music

Traveling

Sports

Cooking

REFERENCES

Dr. MD.ATAUR RAHMAN

Professor,

Department of Mechanical Engineering International Islamic University of Malaysia 53100 KL, Malaysia.

Phone No: - +601135352708.

Engr. MA Zabbar Khan

B.Sc Engg (Mech), PG (Germany), FIEB

Executive Director

Masud Steel Design BD LTD

Email-zabbarkhan@masudsteel.com

Phone No-+8801713122626

